# **ALEJANDRO IGLESIAS**

Francisco de Villagra 127 Ñuñoa, Santiago · +56934863816 alejandroiglesias@gmail.com

Almost 20-year experience in IT, in the financial sector, e-commerce, devops and the native cloud. The last two year I have the chance to be a teacher from a recognized University of Chile, where I put all my efforts to create the teamwork and the agility in the hearth of my students and colleagues.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2019 - 2020

#### TEACHER, UNIVERSIDAD DE VALPARAISO, VALPARAISO CHILE

Teacher of Software Architecture and Web Development for students of 4<sup>th</sup> year.

#### 2018-2021

#### **CLOUD DEVELOPER AND ARCHITECT, TRIFENIX, SANTIAGO CHILE**

We work with native cloud service for build some applications, mainly integrations, our focus is on the efficiency and low cost operations. I worked in different positions, like:

- Developer
- Architect
- Scrum Master
- Product Owner
- Devops Manager

#### 2011-2018

# ARCHITECT, DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT, AND BI LEADER, TSOFT – LATAM

(MEXICO, PERÚ Y CHILE)

Architect, developer, Consultant, Agile Coach, and BI Leader, in companies like:

- Banco Santander Chile
- Banco Santander Mexico
- PEPSICO México
- BCI Chile
- Banco de Crédito del Perú (BCP).
- Transbank Chile
- Banco Security Chile.

#### 2010

#### **DEVELOPER, SERCO LOGISTICS – LA SERENA**

ASP .NET y Ext.js Developer

#### 2006

# **DEVELOPER, LA SOLUCION REPUESTOS**

Winform Developer

2005

**DEVELOPER,** UNIVERSIDAD CATOLICA DEL NORTE, COQUIMBO - CHILE PHP MYSQL Developer.

# **EDUCATION**

2015

MASTER INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES, UNIVERSIDAD SANTA MARÍA, SANTIAGO (NO GRADUATE)

2010

CIVIL COMPUTER ENGINEER, INACAP, LA SERENA

2009

**COMPUTER ENGINEER, INACAP, LA SERENA, CHILE.** 

2008

SISTEMS ANALYST, INACAP, LA SERENA, CHILE.

2002

**NETWORK TECHNICIAN, CEDUC-UCN, COQUIMBO, CHILE.** 

2000

**SOFTWARE DEVELOPERS,** INSTITUTO SUPERIOR DE COMERCIO, COQUIMBO, CHILE (TECHNICAL SECONDARY STUDIES)

#### **ENGLISH LANGUAGE**

Spoken: 60%LISTEN: 70%READ: 90%WRITE: 80%

#### TECHNOLOGIES APPLIED

- ASP .NET MVC
- ASP.NET
- Entity Framework
- SIGNALR
- REDIS
- DEPENDENCY INJECTION
- XUNIT

- REST
- Razor
- GRAPHQL
- SOAP
- AZURE COSMOS DB
- AZURE STORAGE
- AZURE FUNCTIONS

- SQL Server
- ORACLE RACK
- SQL Lite
- C#
- LINQ
- PATTERNS REPOSITORY, CQRS, DDD and SOLID.
- WINFORMS
- FLUTTER
- MOBX
- LINUX
- DOCKER

- AZURE COGNITIVE SEARCH
- Azure Application Insights
- ASPOSE
- TABLEAU
- SQL SERVER ANALYSIS SERVICES
- TEAM FOUNDATION SERVER
- AZURE DEVOPS
- ASPOSE
- REDUX
- REACT

# **ABOUT ME**

I'm a software developer from my fifteen years old (I saw a computer and falling in love, like every person of my kind). In 2005 I learnt Visual Basic .NET, from there, my way has been learning more to be a better developer and contribute to other teams to make it too, with the Microsoft Stack mainly.

During my experience, I have the chance to study 6 careers, understanding that build a software is a culture of continuous learning, the technology is a medium, where the internet is the main resource of knowledge.

After almost 20 years working professionally. I have been put in practice many technologies, always looking for a solution of a big problem, taking decisions constantly. Not all of them has been precise, but every mistake has been the greatest and strong learning I ever had. The resolutions of a lots of big problems in my career is what make strong when I take up a major challenge.

#### **RESOURCES**

- 1. GITHUB
- 2. My University Class Site
- 3. My NPM packages
- 4. My Nuget packages
- 5. Azure Devops